So, when the server respond to your request, it includes a status code, a 3 digit number
that tells you what happened.
Think of status code as the server's way to say, got it, not found or something went wrong.
The five categories status codes are grouped by their first digit.
So first digit will be start with one tablex, which is basically informational, very
clear and when a web application like talking with web socket connection, so during that
web socket connection that request will be made in 101.
Now, 2 doublex, basically it is a successful response and 3 doublex, which is a red direction
response and 4 doublex, basically it is a client error, not your mistakes like it is your
mistakes.
It means a client error, you haven't permission for any kind of resource, for admin kind
of resource or sensitive resources, you don't have any kind of permissions, so five doublex
which is server error, basically it is a server mistakes, not your mistakes.
So now let's talk about common status code, you should know.
So the first status code which you need to know to doublex, 2 doublex, what does it mean?
It means it is successful, it is successful code, it is success, so 200, 200, okay.
Most common status code, 200, okay is the most common status code, everything like work
perfectly, and here what you asked for, like example, you load a web page successfully.
Let me show you, when I did, when I did like, old.com, okay, let's open to open network
tab and do refresh it, and here you can see what I got, 200, okay.
So what does it mean?
It means that this is like my web application or web page successfully loaded, okay.
So now let's talk about 200, okay, basically it means created, when this response will happen,
then you create an account or when you just, so something new was created successfully,
okay.
Example like, you successfully posted a tweet, a new tweet, so that will be made in 201 created,
Now let's talk about, now let's talk about three, double, sorry, let's do it like this,
basically it's, it's read direction, already I have told you, very direct, read direction,
okay.
So basically, what does it mean, 301, it means, moved permanently, moved, moved, okay.
So what does it mean, moved, moved permanently, the web page moved from, has been moved to
a new address, okay, like this is the old page, and this is the new page, okay, like
new address.
So this means that it was moved from this old, old page to new address, old address to new
address, okay, for that time you can see that 301 moved, okay.
Now let me show you an example, it works, sorry, yeah, moved, it works, let's see, yeah,
you can see, what are you able to see, 301 moved permanently, okay.
So basically, this is the read direction, okay.
So one time, at a time, like somewhere around like, 2000 or 2005 to 2010, Google used
this address, acitypsgoogle.com, okay, now they just moved from this acitypsgoogle.com to this
address, acitypsww.google.com, okay, so this is the part of 301 moved permanently, okay.
Now let's talk about 302, we understood 301, now let's talk about 302, so what will happen
in this 302, it means, basically it means found, or you can say it's temporary redirect,
temporary redirect, we talked about permanent redirect, now it's a temporary redirect, okay.
Temporary redirect, now oh sorry, oh this, this one, so temporary right, now what will happen
in this temporary redirect, the page, temporary, like somewhere else, okay.
So basically, this page, temporary is like, like, like a place where, like you are, this
is your home, okay, this is your home, okay, this is your home, and in a same city, and
you are staying at a hotel, okay, let's say hotel, HO, okay, so basically this is a hotel
and this is your home, okay, at same city, but what happened, you are doing some, you are
doing interior renovation of your home, okay, you are doing your interior renovation in
your home, so for that reason you are not able to, like, you are not able to, like, stay
in your home for, because of lots of stuffs over there, right, so for that reason you are
staying temporary at a hotel, okay, when this maintenance will be done, when this maintenance
will be done, interior designing will be done, then you will come back to this again,
so for that, for this is the, this is the example basically, okay, so this is how, when
like, the page is temporary somewhere else, so example maintenance derived, okay, so they
are, they are doing something, something changes, so for at that time it will, you will,
you will, you will able to see that, three zero, three, three or two found, which means
temporary right, okay, now let us talk about, three zero four, three zero four, where
it means, not modified, the page
hasn't changed, since you last visited, okay, so browser use catchy version faster, so
what will happen, like, let's say, like Google.com, okay, Google.com, they haven't,
like, it haven't changed, okay, when you, when you did last visit, last visit, okay,
so basically, let's say example, you are going to your friend's home, okay, and for, for
like, you want to meet up with your friend, okay, so you, once upon a time you, you,
you just visited his home, near about five years ago, okay, and after that, you again,
you want to again visit, today, okay, so what will happen, you just, in 2020, okay, in 2020,
whatever you just saw in a, in his home, okay, this will be the same, there will be the
same thing, again and again, in, in his home, okay, so in 2020, in 2025, that is the,
like, fully, fully, fully, same things, like, he, he doesn't change the wall paint,
he doesn't change the, like, change the, like, change anything, he doesn't change anything
in his home, okay, so that is a part of, not modified, three or four, not modified, so
now let's talk about, now let's talk about four double X, basically four double X means
client error quotes, client error quotes, okay, now what does it mean client error quotes,
basically, it's your problem, okay, so the first word which will be face four double
O, four double O, which means bad request, okay, which means bad request, so why, why this
will happen, bad request, basically your request was invalid or malformed, and I don't
understand what you are saying for, okay, and example, you said data in the wrong format,
so at that time, this will happen, this four double O will happen, okay, bad, bad request,
now let's talk about, four O, one, four O, one, what does it mean, four O, one, it means
unauthorized, unauthorized, unauthorized, yeah, unauthorized, okay, so when, when you got this unauthorized
four O, one status code, during, you need to log in first, okay, and it was asking you
to, who are you, show me your credentials, and in example, like trying to access your profile
without log in in, okay, without log in in, so at that time you will face this four O, one
unauthorized, okay, so you need to enter the credentials properly, then you can, you can do
what, in your profile, now, now let's talk about four O, three, four O, three, which means
forbidden, which means forbidden, forbidden, when you will face this four O, three, forbidden,
you are logged in, but you don't have permissions, okay, when you are logged in, but you
don't have permissions, like you logged in in user, user role, and you want to do changes,
and you want to do changes in admin, so at that time you need to upgrade your profile from
user to admin, like if you, if you don't do this, then you will, you will, you will
able to see that four O, three, forbidden, okay, you cannot see the admin access, or admin
stuffs directly, without getting the admin access, okay, now let's say, now another thing
was four O, four, I hope you are, you guys are familiar with this four O, four, so basically
it means not found, not found, so the page doesn't exist basically, okay, when the page
doesn't exist, doesn't exist, like it will, it will say I can't, I can't find what
we're looking for, example, example clicking on a broken link, or typing wrong URL, okay,
so at that time you will face this four O, four, four, four, now let's talk about five
double x, now let's talk about five double x, five double x, what does it mean, it means
internal server error, okay, internal server error, okay,
internal server, so when it, when this will happen, internal server error, so something broke
on the server, okay, something broke on the server, it's not your fault basically, guys,
it's a totally server fault, server site fault, okay, so it will say like, oops, something
went wrong on our end, okay, examples of work code has a book, so at that time you will
be able to see this, like, like 500, 500, which is i s e, which is internal server
error, okay, now let's talk about our next status code code, which is 5002, okay, so what does
it mean 5002, it means bad request, sorry, bad gateway, it's not request, already we did
bad request, which is like, already we talked about gateway, bad gateway, so what will happen
in this five or two bad gateway, so server received invalid response from another server,
and example, example server trying to contact data with what failing, okay, at that time, this
will happen, now let's talk about 5,0003, okay, 503, which is service service, service
unavailable, okay, service unavailable, so at this time 503, service unavailable, server
is temporarily down or overloaded, we are too busy right now trying again later, okay, so
at that time you are getting this 503, which is like server is temporary down or overloaded
example websites under having heavy traffic, so at that time you will able to see this 503,
so now let's now let's understand what we did, here is the quick memory tricks, okay,
so basically 200, okay, success, everything is too good, 300, red irate, go three
doors down, okay, 400, which is your fault for you to fix, okay, so and then 5w, which
is server fault 5w on server, okay, so this was the thing in status mode, thank you guys.